Dhumketu PRESENTS
GOD CREATED HUMANS
THEN REALIZED THEY WERE UNHAPPY
AND SENT THEM THE DOMS
THEY MIGRATED, PLAYED MUSIC, AND SANG
IN THE HOPE OF TOUCHING HEARTS...
You're useless! Damn it!
Come here!
What am I supposed to do with this bull?
We already had two!
Don't be like that, Sefure.
That bull's dick is what feeds us.
Come on! If you took care
of your own instead of the bull's,
maybe we'd have a kid now.
Stop embarrassing me!
I won't! Why would I stop? Come here!
- Piroz, get out of the way!
- Come on.
- This bull pimp is driving me insane.
- You're causing a scene. Such a shame.
- I'm no bull pimp!
- You are!
I'm Kalender the Breeder!
- Breed, then!
- Everyone knows me!
- I swear... I'm leaving.
- Let me beat him.
There you are!
Come on, Piroz. Come, my man.
Bring it over here.
Let's show it to Mürşit Aga.
You see, aga?
I'm going to do it just like this. There.
It's going to be that easy.
All right? Okay.
Come on. Hold him, boys.
Hold him.
Hold the man.
Let's see which tooth it is.
Open wide. There you go.
A bit more, man.
There it is. See? This one.
Hang on. Don't move your jaw.
Hang on. I got it!
See?
The roots are as big as a bull's horns.
The top is rotten, but still.
Hogir!
What is it, Hatun?
Your father ran away again.
What?
Take it, aga. Take your tooth.
Let's go get him.
This will ease your pain, all right?
Let's go. We'll be back, aga.
I'm going to push open your door.
I'll wipe the mud off my shoes
and enter your home.
And I'll say, "Dilo! Here I am!"
"I'm here, Dilo," I'll say.
"I'm in your home."
Weren't you with your grandpa last night?
He made me write down a poem,
then went to bed.
Damn it.
Take the lower road
so we can cut him off, man.
- All right.
- Damn it, Grandpa.
He just can't help himself.
You'll stare at me.
You'll stare at me and think.
You'll gaze upon the flowers
and then look at me.
And you'll say, "Mirze! Let's go, Mirze."
Dad!
Damn it. It's the kids.
- Dad!
- Stay out of my way, kids!
Dad, stop.
Stay out of my way.
You're going to embarrass us!
Leave me alone, kid!
Why would you be embarrassed?
Hogir.
- Hogir.
- What?
He says he's going after Dilo.
Tell him we should just go back,
and we'll bring Dilo to the village.
- Will he buy that?
- He will.
If not, we'll have to make him go back.
Dad, let's go back to the tent.
No! I'm going to get Dilo.
Stay out of my way.
Come on, Dad!
Stop saying "Dad" and get out of my way!
Don't you dare.
Don't, Dad. What are you doing?
- Leave me alone.
- Don't, Dad. I'm going to fall.
Leave.
Look, Dad.
Mom just died,
and you're going after some woman.
She's not some woman. Dilo is mine.
Come on.
How can you tarnish
the memory of our late mother?
Shame on you, Dad. It's wrong.
What?
Your mother passed away.
But I've always loved Dilo.
They wouldn't let me have her.
If they had...
your mother wouldn't be your mother.
Enough already. Hey, Piroz.
We're playing tonight, right?
You go get the instruments ready.
Come on, Nedim.
Come here.
I swear... What are we going to do with him?
Anyway, let's just go.
What's that?
A wedding dress.
I hate the color.
Honey, all wedding dresses are white.
No other options?
Just put it on.
Look. You once left our home
without a dress.
You've embarrassed us.
There can be no wedding without a dress.
There's a wedding?
Will I get to dance too?
Of course you will, honey.
Please put it on.
All right. I will if you two leave.
The bride, Sümbül,
isn't so keen to get married.
Just don't play any sad songs.
Keep it lively. Very lively, even.
Let's not upset anyone.
Don't you worry, aga.
We'll play so well
that the bride's late grandparents
will rise from their graves and dance.
Please keep the zurna going all night.
Don't worry, aga.
We'll play it non-stop.
If you perform well tonight,
I'll give you two rams instead of one.
All right, aga.
You can rest assured. Don't worry.
All right. Good luck.
Thank you.
- Hogir.
- Yeah?
I need to go take a leak.
All right. Just hurry back.
Sümbül?
Come on, honey.
What are you doing?
Look at him play. Come here, you.
Stop it, Uncle.
What's going on, Piroz?
Nothing, man.
- Let's play well tonight.
- Okay.
Very well.
- Of course.
- Nedim.
I don't have the lungs for it.
You play the zurna tonight.
- I'll never stop.
- Nice.
Remember, the best man
asked for cheerful songs only.
If you're ever stuck, leave it to me.
I'll lead tonight.
All right.
Don't wait here, kids. Go!
Come on. Let's go.
Hello.
Are you the groom?
Yes.
You have a nice suit.
I put it on for you.
Would you do anything for me?
I would.
What's that?
Honey, stop.
He's your man.
Can you do that?
I can.
Do it, then.
You sound like a donkey.
I'm your husband now. Watch your mouth.
Talk some sense into your daughter
so that she knows how to treat me.
- Here they are.
- Yeah.
Who holds a wedding for a lunatic?
- Here's the lunatic.
- Such a shame.
Here goes the lunatic.
Who are you calling a lunatic?
Piroz!
They're fighting.
We have to keep playing. Come on.
One, two. One, two, three, four!
Try not to worry about it too much.
I didn't do anything wrong.
Whoever wronged her,
whoever did this to her,
God damn him to hell.
You think the girl is a virgin,
then all of a sudden,
she's about to give birth.
Don't worry, aga.
Just try to keep a clear head.
Farewell.
Thank you. Off you go.
Good luck.
Take care.
Come on, girl. Let's go.
He's waking up.
Come on, Piroz. Get up.
You're finally awake.
Did they really have to fight?
It cost us a ram.
- Where's the bride?
- What bride?
The bride from the wedding, man.
- They went that way.
- Seriously?
Where did they go, Hogir?
The groom's taking her back to her father.
- Hogir.
- What?
- That bride...
- Yeah?
- She's the one for me.
- What do you mean?
She fell in love with me,
and I fell in love with her.
Seriously?
When?
Well, just before the wedding.
Hogir, we have to find a way.
What do you want us to do, Piroz?
The groom is taking her back.
You know,
because she turned out to be impure.
- Impure?
- Yeah.
Thank God!
- Hogir.
- Yeah?
I just know her heart is pure.
How?
I told you, man.
Her heart called out to me.
We have to figure something out, then.
- There's a way, you know.
- What?
- Let's go ask for her father's blessing.
- You're right. Let's do it.
We'll ask him properly.
The groom is taking her back anyway.
She's not married.
It's within our rights.
Yes. It is.
Let's turn back and go to his place.
Slow down.
Let's go back to the village first.
Let's ask Dad.
Let's see what Mr. Mirze says.
- Right. Dad.
- Yeah.
Dad!
Dad.
What the...
Who ties up his own father, Hogir?
Untie me, kids.
Let me go get Dilo.
Sure, Dad.
- Dad.
- What?
I promise you
I'm going to go get Dilo for you.
You promise?
I promise. I swear.
I have news, Dad.
Your son fell in love with a gazelle.
- Piroz?
- Yeah?
She's a gazelle, huh?
She is, Dad.
Are her ankles thin?
Like a stork's.
When shall we go get your gazelle?
- Let's go tomorrow, Dad.
- Yay.
Well, then,
let's go make our day brighter tomorrow.
I wanted to be your son-in-law.
Your daughter brought shame on you.
Will you handle it, or shall I?
Sümbül is my daughter.
It is my responsibility
to restore our honor.
It's too hot. Put some more cold water.
Your father and your brother's debauchery
is going to get us in trouble, Hogir.
Mom, find a girl for me too.
Shut up! It's not your business.
Why are you hitting him?
If nothing goes wrong,
we'll handle Piroz's business tomorrow.
What about your father, then?
What are we going to do about him?
He's walking around with a boner all day!
What are you doing, for God's sake?
We'll figure that out as well.
Here you go.
What a nice home for us.
You should
Love roses
Love violets too
But don't forget
Violets are coy
Yet roses are yours
Hey, Hogir.
Who is this girl? Where are we going?
She's Seymen Aga's daughter.
We were at her wedding yesterday,
but the groom took her back.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
So he's going to give us his blessing?
Sure. Why wouldn't he?
She's not married.
The groom took her back.
- We'll just ask. It'll be fine.
- Yeah.
The heart does what the heart desires.
- Hey, Mirze.
- What?
Is that what happened with Dilo?
You... Listen to me, you bull pimp.
Her heart has always been with me,
so I don't know
what you're talking about, you dick.
Don't be like that.
I helped Seymen Aga with his cows once.
Yeah?
Her daughter was so beautiful and elegant.
She was radiant.
She brought light wherever she walked.
Dad.
Come on. Let's not be late.
The tambourine and the kemane?
All packed, Mirze.
We should have our instruments with us
so we can speak our minds.
Hey, Piroz.
Is Dilo going to join us afterwards
to see the bride?
Dad, is Dilo my mother?
Why would I show her the bride?
Shut up, kid!
She's your mother too.
Whoever your father loves is your mother.
You're such a devil, Piroz.
- Hang on, Kalender.
- What's up?
I have a question.
I'm sure we can handle this,
but what are we going to do with Dad?
What should I do?
Why? What's wrong with him?
We promised him we'd bring Dilo over.
Didn't you tell him Dilo had a husband,
and she's dead?
If we tell him Dilo's dead,
I swear he'll bring hell upon us.
Say, "She walked towards the light," then.
You're so funny.
Kalender, come on. Please, man.
Please help us out.
I know a way.
Your father is in heat.
Prayers and charms won't help him.
What should we do, then?
All good breeders know this.
When a bull is in heat,
you show him the hay.
Let's get this over with
and go back to the village at once, then.
- Sure.
- Right?
Let's go. Come on.
You shouldn't have done this to us.
What did we do wrong?
This is not who we are.
Why did you soil our honor?
What is not who we are?
We'll clean it up if it's soiled, Mom.
Get me a bucket. I'll wash it up.
What did you do, honey?
Who did this to you?
I have a kid
His shirt is white
He hops around like a goat
He sees a gazelle
And chases her
He doesn't know whom to ask
But he still needs to ask
So here he is before you
Seymen Aga
Mirze the Posha.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
If you have something to say,
say it like a man so I can understand.
Dad, be clearer.
Come on, people.
Don't let your kid be heartbroken
Don't let my kid be heartbroken
Don't let my kid sleep alone
Don't let your kid sleep alone
Seymen Aga
Mirze the Posha!
Dad, just be straight with him.
But how?
I don't know how to say it.
Look, Seymen Aga.
Is Sümbül your daughter?
Yes.
Is Piroz my kid?
- I suppose he is.
- He is.
My kid's heart
aches for your daughter Sümbül.
What do you mean?
What he's trying to say
is that by God's will,
we ask for your blessing
to marry your daughter Sümbül
to our boy Piroz.
I see. I understand.
How nice. As long as
one understands the other,
what more could we ask for, right?
Look, Mirze the Posha.
You came here as friends,
but you won't leave as such.
Why did he say that?
I'm not sure, Dad.
Rıza!
Who's Rıza?
Yes, Father?
Call your brothers over.
All right, Father.
He has a lot of brothers.
Maybe they want to be together for this.
It would've been better
if they at least spared Mirze.
Yes, but Dad was very upfront with him.
Piroz is his son, after all.
Why didn't you throw a single punch?
Grandpa, they were grown men.
Who cares?
Aren't you strong?
You're useless.
Go slower, damn it!
All right. There we go.
I swear, Sefure...
I swear it looks just like you.
You think hay can substitute
for a loved one?
Why not? It can if you need it to.
Have a kid with that, then.
All right?
Go ahead.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
I'll do just that. You'll see.
- Will I now?
- You will.
- I already saw.
- What did you see?
I'm still seeing it.
What are you seeing, Sefure?
Or rather, I keep looking,
but I'm failing to see anything.
What am I supposed to see anyway?
You dickless pimp.
- God damn you.
- Stop, Sefure!
Hang on.
- I'm so unlucky.
- Stop!
Leave!
- Write it down, Nedim.
- Write what down, Grandpa?
You should love roses
Love violets too
But don't forget, violets are coy
Yet roses are yours
Hey, Dad.
Let me see.
- Dad.
- What?
But don't forget, violets are coy
Yet roses are yours
- Dad.
- Yeah?
It's Dilo.
What happened to her?
Nothing, Dad.
Don't tell me she's dead.
Of course not, Dad. God forbid.
Dad, I brought her to you.
This right here is what I call a good kid.
Where's Dilo?
Which ones were the coy ones?
Where is she?
Where is Dilo?
See, Dad, Dilo is a bit sick.
That's okay. I'll take care of her.
Not that kind of sick.
I mean, you can see her,
but you can't go near her.
You can talk to her,
but you can't hear her.
And, Dad, the doctor said
if you were to go touch Dilo,
Dilo would die.
You should
Love roses
Listen, Dad.
Don't you cross that line, all right?
The doctor said so.
"Dilo will die if he crosses it," he said.
All right. Leave me alone with Dilo.
Let me pray for her and talk to her.
Let's go.
I'll just stay here
and pray.
Dilo?
Dilo, welcome.
Welcome, Dilo.
Are you ill?
I'm glad you're here.
I'm so glad.
You're not ill, are you? You're okay.
Your tears
Are mixed up with my own
Your eyelashes touch my heart
Don't say anything
Stop
Don't you dare talk
Your heart is already singing to my heart
Like a nightingale
So?
Are you relieved, Dad?
Of course.
More so than reuniting itself,
just saying what you have to say
is what brings real relief.
What am I going to do, Dad?
Pick up your kemane
and go say what you have to say.
Don't bottle it up.
If she loves you...
she will go with you.
What do you mean?
Should I just go visit my gazelle?
It's about time you did.
Go to her while your heart is still warm.
You're here.
Yes, I am.
Rıza.
Make it quick.
Just handle it quietly
without attracting people.
All right, Father.
We'll handle the rest later.
We'll say she killed herself.
Yes. Let's do that.
They got spooked?
You scared them.
We scared them.
Don't you worry.
They can't do anything.
- What are we going to do?
- We're going to elope.
- You have a beautiful smile.
- You make me smile.
There's a jinni or something.
Where?
In the barn.
How did that happen?
How would I know?
Come with me.
Come on.
We should get an imam to pray for her.
The poor girl.
Let's get the hodja from the village.
Get Kalender the Posha here.
Poor girl is possessed by a jinni.
- It's so strange.
- She needs a hodja to pray for her.
Look at her.
I put the hay in and filled it up
All the power to the bull's dick
Kalender? There you are. Hey, Kalender.
It's important.
What the hell do you want?
It's important, Kalender.
Did your father run away again?
No, man. Sümbül's father
is going to invite you.
I see. He needs help with a cow?
No, man. No cows.
He thinks Sümbül is possessed.
By an actual demon?
No. I'm the one who possessed her.
You're the real devil anyway, Piroz.
Stop it, Kalender.
We don't have time for jokes.
You have to help me.
I have a solution.
What is it?
We're going to kill Sümbül before they do.
That's your solution?
Why would we kill my gazelle?
We'll make it look like we did.
They'll think she's dead,
so they won't kill her.
Oh... I don't get it.
I'll give her a potion.
She will seem dead for a day.
Seymen will believe it,
so he won't kill her.
The rest is up to you.
Oh... I get it.
I mean, I'm up for it
if she's not going to die.
She's not.
- Leave me alone.
- Thank you, Kalender!
Stop it. Just leave, kid.
You're the man.
Shoo. Go away.
Good luck.
You're going to die.
What do you mean?
I mean, we're going to kill you.
Can Seymen Aga kill you if we do it first?
He can't.
And then I'm going to elope with you.
You'll leave me and elope with my corpse?
Don't you love me?
Come on.
It's not that.
I do love you.
It's just that you're going to die,
but actually,
you're not going to die.
All right.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Give that to me.
What's troubling her?
Whenever we go inside,
we hear strange noises.
Sümbül is possessed.
I'll go pray for her.
I'll get rid of the demon right away.
Stay here.
Don't come in.
Let me check her first.
I need to know
if it's a demon I'm acquainted with.
All right? You pray here.
Don't stop.
Keep praying!
It's not a demon. It's something else.
I mean, it is a demon,
but it's something else.
Indeed, a demon,
but something else.
It's inside her.
It's made her body its home.
It even built a swing in there.
It's just enjoying itself.
It keeps swinging.
It won't leave before dawn.
There's no way.
Oh, Sümbül!
You were never happy.
You never had any luck.
I wish I died instead.
Just get up. I'll die instead.
Father.
It's pesticide.
She killed herself.
All right. It's what she deserved.
She punished her wrongdoings herself.
- Did she really deserve this?
- Just shut up, woman.
Rıza.
Let's bury her
as soon as possible, all right?
All right, Father.
You're God's guest.
You belong here now.
Your father has a heart of stone.
He was even willing to kill you.
We're the same now, you and I.
Piroz is my son,
and you're my daughter.
I should go.
Dilo's waiting for me.
Hey, Mr. Piroz!
You do whatever you want, don't you?
Quiet, Hatun. I'll explain.
Did you get yourself into trouble?
I didn't. I just brought
the one I love here.
Please don't tell anyone.
You shut up.
Did you come here willingly?
Yes.
All right. That's good.
If you came here willingly,
it's our job to keep you safe.
What is this?
I'll bring you some clothes.
Don't walk around wearing a rag.
Remember what I said before?
No one will harm you here.
Grandpa!
He's not here.
Uncle, who's this?
Who's who?
Isn't this the girl you wanted?
No. It's not her.
It is her.
No, it's not.
I swear it's her, Uncle.
I said no. Just get out, you rascal.
So... Where was I?
"No one will harm you here."
Right. Yeah.
Look.
I wore this once
and never again.
It was meant for you, Sümbül.
Oh, my.
God must be on your side, Sümbül.
It's lucky to have a man like Piroz.
I'm not so sure
whether Hogir was in love with me or not.
He just told me he'd marry me.
He got me
in exchange for an ox and a zurna.
Then the ox died,
and all that's left was the zurna.
My late father
kept playing that zurna for years.
He always said,
"Honey, whenever I play it at a wedding,
I think of you,
and feel bad deep inside."
That's what he used to say,
but he was actually sad about the dead ox.
Oh, honey.
You look gorgeous.
Like a partridge.
Oh, partridge
I fell in love with you, partridge
And you with me, partridge
Oh, partridge
The ring is not the place
for fledglings, old ones, and sick ones.
Don't make a partridge
participate in more than three matches.
Oh, partridge
I fell in love with you, partridge
And you with me, partridge
Oh, partridge
- Dad.
- What do you want?
- Dad!
- What the hell do you want?
- I went to Grandpa's tent.
- Hang on!
Everyone stop! And?
And then...
- Then I saw...
- What did you see?
I saw Uncle Piroz inside.
- So?
Remember the girl
we tried to go and get for him?
- Yes.
- Her brothers beat us up.
Yeah.
I saw her.
What?
What did you do, Piroz?
What was I supposed to do?
Should I have let them kill her?
You're going to get us into trouble.
Meaning?
It goes,
"No matter what we do,
God's will shall be done."
What are you doing here?
It's not appropriate
to discuss it in front of her.
Get out.
Leave, all of you. Go!
Come on. Stop staring. Just go.
Damn it, Piroz.
You're really something else.
You just stole the girl
as if she were a hen.
What was I supposed to do?
Should I have left the one I love there?
Never mind my love for her,
should I have left her to die?
He would've done it if he wanted to,
but the Almighty had other plans.
Mashallah.
- Say mashallah, Hogir.
- Mashallah.
She's not going anywhere.
I'm together with the one I love too.
Nothing bad happened.
But, Dad,
we'll get into trouble.
We won't!
No one can give us any trouble.
It is not your concern.
It's mine and my son's concern only,
if anything.
All right, Dad.
Whatever you say.
We should marry them, then.
- We should?
- We should.
Thank God!
What was it...
What's your father's name?
- Seymen.
I know.
You, Sümbül, daughter of Seymen,
do you take Piroz, son of Mirze,
as your husband?
I do.
You, Piroz, son of Mirze...
Oh, you...
So, hereby, in the presence of God,
I declare you husband and wife.
- Hogir.
- Yeah?
Is it okay if I recite Al-Fatiha?
Hatun?
- Sefure?
- What?
- He wants to recite Al-Fatiha.
- Sure. It's the intention that counts.
Go ahead, then. A prayer is a prayer.
Then, Al-Fatiha!
All praise is for Allah
Lord of all worlds
The Most Compassionate, Most Merciful
Master of the Day of Judgment
You alone we worship
And You alone we ask for help
Guide us along the Straight Path
The Path of those You have blessed
Not of those You are displeased with
Or of those who are astray
- Amen.
Piroz, congratulations.
Look at it.
It looks amazing.
Stunning. It's beautiful, aga.
Look, aga.
Only kings have better teeth.
You know what you're doing, Hogir.
You are even a bigger aga now, aga.
Let me tell you something, aga.
You know, your wives
are going to notice it.
The younger one asked for this anyway.
Maybe the older one wants something too.
Come by whenever you want.
We're always ready.
Who's that girl?
Oh, her? She's Fahri's daughter.
She's our bride now.
She's Piroz's wife.
She doesn't look like you.
She seems familiar, but...
No, aga. You must be mistaken.
She's Fahri's daughter.
Anyway.
What do I owe you?
We can settle it
for a two-year-old ram, aga.
All right.
It was definitely Sümbül.
You sure you're not mistaken?
I'm sure.
I know your daughter.
Thanks, Mürşit. Thank you.
I'm not one to lie or play tricks.
I'll handle it.
Do that.
You know what to do.
Yes. I do.
Let me die with you
Let me burn with you
I've been through hell already
Let me in your heaven now
Come. Come be mine.
Will you be mine?
Hush.
Don't talk.
Love me.
But won't people talk?
Huh?
I don't need to speak.
Let me die with you.
Dilo?
Dilo...
Dilo!
Damn you, kids!
Why did you do this to me, kids?
You kids never realized
what your father's heart ached for!
I don't want to burn you, but...
Let me die.
Let me die with you.
Dad!
You're a bottle made of glass
Come fall into my arms
I've been seeing you every day for years,
yet you're still so beautiful.
- Dad.
- To hell with your dad!
Grandpa...
- What is it?
- He burned it down.
- Grandpa torched Dilo, Dad.
- What?
How could he do that?
Just go let your uncle know.
- Hogir, get up.
- Hand me my shirt.
- Damn it, Dad. You're driving me insane.
- God knows what he'll do next.
- I swear he's crazy.
- Might as well torch me too, Dad.
I built us a home, Dilo.
Our flowers are waiting for us.
It'll be as if we can touch the sky there.
There will always be a breeze too.
Birds will put us to sleep.
Dilo, aren't you going to say something?
Hey. Are you mad at me?
All right.
You're my Dilo.
You're the real Dilo to me.
I did tell you to watch them.
You didn't watch your father,
nor your brother.
Hatun, I'm begging you. Please shut up.
I'm trying to find out if he's dead,
and you're berating me.
Here. Let's put your legs this way.
Look at you.
Are you comfortable, Dilo?
He must be dead.
There are no teeth or anything.
- Piroz!
- He wouldn't burn himself.
- What is it?
Piroz.
Seymen's coming here with his men.
Where did you see them?
They were asking around in Zümrüt
where the tents were.
As if we needed more trouble.
They will kill us.
Oh, right!
Hey, Nedim.
- You know where Grandpa's grave is?
- Yes, Dad.
Go check if he's there.
I'll recite you a poem
before we go to sleep, all right?
I've opened my heart to you, Dilo
Let your dust land upon my heart
Let me look at your eyes
And close mine
Let our breaths intertwine
The shroud of this world is suffocating
My love for you is eternal
All right.
Let's go to sleep, shall we?
Grandpa!
Damn it.
You lot won't let me go to heaven
with Dilo at my side.
- Grandpa.
- What?
- Seymen's coming to the village.
- What? Where?
Get up, Grandpa. Let's go.
Come on, Grandpa.
Dilo, come on.
Let's go save our kid's love.
Let's go.
Piroz got us into this trouble.
Come on. Not you too, Sefure.
What? I swear to God,
Seymen won't let us live.
Dad? Look!
- Mirze?
- He's coming.
- There he is.
- Dad!
- It's Mirze.
- It's him.
It's Mirze.
Dad!
Oh, Dad.
- Here. Hold it.
- Give it to me.
- Hang on, girl.
- Come, Grandpa.
Dad? You're alive?
Of course I am, kid.
If I die,
I'll die with Dilo.
Come on.
There we go.
- Dad.
- What?
You know Seymen's coming, right?
Yeah, Dad. He and his men.
We need to go.
I have a solution if you'll listen.
- What?
- What is it?
It's the only solution.
- Tell us, Dad.
- I have one condition.
Okay. What is it?
You're going to let me
stay here with Dilo.
Oh, come on.
What are you talking about, Dad?
Cross the Kinik River
before sunrise.
- Kinik?
- Yeah.
Take the raft
and leave it on the other side.
You'll reach the Deriz Plateau
before the day is over.
I'm going to stay here with Dilo.
You can't do that, Dad.
Sure I can.
I'll distract Seymen.
Dad.
Dad, stop being so stubborn.
Just take Dilo and come with us.
No, kid. That won't work.
I'll be here with Dilo. No.
If Seymen Aga comes here,
you'll know it in your hearts.
Grandpa, come with us.
Listen. Look after the kid.
You have a long journey ahead.
Very long.
Just go.
Take them across the river.
- Dad.
- Yeah?
Keep this with you, then.
No. I don't want it.
Just leave my kemane.It's my soul.
All right.
Listen, Mirze.
You go. I'll stay.
He's coming for me.
Why would you die in my stead?
Don't say that, honey.
You're so young.
But I...
I'm more than halfway dead anyway.
You are one with my son.
Off you go.
Here you go. There.
Your daughter
is in love with my kid, Seymen Aga.
Why would she love that bastard of yours?
Don't be like that, Seymen Aga.
The heart does not discriminate.
Where's the bastard?
With the one he loves. With his gazelle.
Who knows
whichever mountain they're climbing.
Mirze the Posha, I swear I'll shoot you.
Stop, Seymen Aga. Wait.
I swear I'll shoot!
Let me sing to you.
Maybe it'll make you listen to your heart.
What do you say?
I have a kid, a son
Light shines on his white shirt
Mirze the Posha!
I will shoot you!
I have no idea
Whichever mountain they're climbing...
Are you going to tell me where he is?
I'll shoot you!
The hearts of our kids, Seymen Aga
Are bound together
Let's go.
Let's honor Mirze properly.
- Hogir.
- Yeah?
Whatever happens happens.
Let's go back.
Let's give him a proper burial.
All right, Piroz. Let's go back.
Seyran, my dear
Take off your shoes
Let's go in the room
Like I said
Seyran's breasts are like
The shade of a snow fountain
The room is cold
Oh, my crazy one
It's been seven years
I've been waiting for you
Oh, my crazy one
Seyran, my dear
Take off your shoes
Let's go in the room
Like I said
Seyran's breasts are like
The shade of a snow fountain
The room is cold
Oh, my crazy one
It's been seven years
I've been waiting for you
Oh, my crazy one
Subtitle translation by:
Dhumket